Edward G. Ramberg Papers 1916-1994 Mss.Ms.Coll.88
American Philosophical Society
- Series II. Personal, 1916-1991; 1.0 Linear feet
  - High School Report Card, 1920-1922; 1 item; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 4)
  - Inventory of Ramberg Villa, 1920, 1929; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 4)
    Original August 1920, Duplicate October, 1929
  - K Theresien Gymnasium München -- School Reports, 1916-1918; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 4)
  - Lecture at the Norwegian Institute of Technology, Trondheim, Norway, 1961; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 4)
  - Lincoln High School report card, 1921, 1922; 4 items; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 4)
  - Memorandum book, 1928; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 4)
  - National Service Board for Religious Objectors, 1944; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 4)
    Grant to leave
  - Notes and articles, 1928-1934; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 4)
  - "Philosophy and Philosophers", 1957; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 4)
  - Philosophy paper, 1928; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 4)
  - Photographs, Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 4)
  - Reed College transcript, n.d.; 2 items; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 4)
  - School program, 1924-1925; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 4)
  - Student identification, 1930/1931; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 4)
  - World War II and Religious Objectors, 1942-1943; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 4)
  - Passport, 1920; 1 item; Ramberg, Lucy (Box 4)
  - School records, 1924, 1925; Ramberg, Sarah Sargent (Box 4)
  - Society of the Sigma Xi. Cornell University Chapter, 1930; 2 items (Box 4)
  - 1960-1961, Technische Hochscule Darmstadt (Box 4)
- Series III. RCA, 1927-1973; 1.0 Linear feet
  The RCA series consists of notes and articles on Ramberg's research, including a substantial number of reprints by Ramberg and his colleagues at RCA relating to his work in electron optics, kinescopes, metallurgy, and other scientific fields, and copies of two of his books. Among the correspondents and authors in Series III are V. K. Zworykin, James Hillier, A. W. Vance, George A. Morton, and Arnold Sommerfeld. A few of the articles were actually written by Ramberg prior to his employment at RCA, although he included them in his RCA files.
  Of some note in the Series is the copy of an interview with Ramberg on his retirement from RCA in 1972, in which Ramberg reflects on his career and his thoughts on science and social responsibility. There are also miscellaneous research notes on electron optics and other topics, mementoes from annual RCA dinners during the late 1950s. Also worthy of note are materials relating to a lawsuit that Ramberg joined, in which 186 plaintiffs from 22 countries attempted to sue the U.S. and USSR to limit the proliferation of nuclear weapons. There is correspondence from Francis Heisler and Ralph B. Atkinson, attorneys in the case, and a brief history of the suit from its beginnings with Linus Pauling in 1958.
  - "Thermal Conductivity of Geranium in the Temperature Range 300-1080 K" Journal Physical Chem Solids 8, 340-343., 1959; Abeles, Benjamin (Box 5)
  - 1960, Adams, G. F. (Box 5)
  - Who's Who in Engineering, n.d.; American Association of Engineering Societies. (Box 5)
  - "Potential Distribution of Symmetrical Cylindrical Electron Lenses" British Journal of Applied Physics 5: 179-181., 1954; Archard, G.D. (Box 5)
  - "Unsere Verantwortung im Atomzeitalter," Halbmonatsschrift Stimme der Gemeinde., Bechert, Karl, 1901-1981 (Box 5)
  - "Visual Capacity An Image Quality Descriptor for Display Evaluation" RCA Company Private Technical Report, 1-35., 1973; Cohen, R.W. and I. Gorog (Box 5)
  - Membership, n.d.; Electron Microscope Society of America. (Box 5)
  - David Sarnoff Award, 1961; Enstrom, Elmer W. (Box 5)
  - "Lenses for Effecting An Apparent Lateral Displacement of An Axial Object Point as Function of the Inclination of the Imaging Rays: Optical Simulation of Degrouping in Color Kinescopes" RCA Laboratories Technical Report: PTR-807: 1-30., 1958; Briggs, J. A.; Epstein, D.W.; Kraus, P. E.; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 5)
  - 1937, Genon, R. Musson (Box 5)
  - "New Color Projection System" Journal of the Optical Society of America. 48, no. 11, Incomplete., 1958; Glenn, William E. (Box 5)
  - "The Use of Semiconductors in Thermoelectric Refrigeration" British Journal of Applied Physics, 386-390., 1954; Douglas, R.W.; Goldsmid, H.J. (Box 5)
  - "A New Approach to Color Television Display and Color Selection Using A Sealed Light Valve" Proceedings of the National Electronics Conference 24: 771-773., Good, William E. (Box 5)
  - "Principles of Simultaneous-Color Projection Television Fluid Deformation" Journal of the SMPTE. 79, 788-794., 1970; Good, William E. (Box 5)
  - "Single Gun Color TV Projector" Proceedings of Electron Optical Systems Design Conference, September 16-18, 1969, New York, NY, 74-78., Good, William E.; True, Thomas T. (Box 5)
  - "Recent Advances in Photoemission" Electronics and Electron Physics., 1959; Gorlich, P. (Box 5)
  - "Die geometrisch-optische Intensitätsverteilung im Brennfleck des abgelenkten Elektronenstrahlbundel" Optik 11, 32-43., 1954; Grumm, H. (Box 5)
  - "Electron Microscope" Encyclopaedia Britannica: 1-16., 1948; Hillier, James (Box 5)
  - "Kontrasterhühung in der Elektronenmikroskopie" Physik 2 Band 7 Heft: 273-278., 1950; Hillier, James; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 5)
  - "The Magnetic Electron Microscope Objective: Contour Phenomena and the Attainment of High Resolving Power" Journal of Applied Physics 18 No. 1: 48-71., 1947; Hillier, James; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 5)
  - "The Photographic Action of Electrons in the Range Between 40 and 212 Kilovolts" Journal of Applied Physics 13, No. 7: 450-456., 1943; Hillier, James; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 5)
  - "Microanalysis by Means of Electrons" Journal of Applied Physics 15, No. 9: 663-675., 1944; Baker, Richard F.; Hillier, James (Box 5)
  - 1961, Hora, H. (Box 5)
  - "Elektromagnetische Wellen in Medien mit stetig verländerlicher Brechzahl"., 1960; Hora, H. (Box 5)
  - "Zur Seituenversetzung bei der Total reflexion von Materiewellen" Optik 17. Band, Seite 409-415., 1960; Hora, H. (Box 5)
  - "Besonderheiten der Temperaturabhangigheit der Photoemission von Multialikathoden" Zeitschrift Fur Naturforschung, Band 15 a, Heft 11, 1014-1016., 1960; Frischmuth-Hoffman, G.; Gorlich, P.; Hora, H. (Box 5)
  - "Effect of the Polarization of the Incident Light on the Emission of Complex Photocathodes" a Russian Journal, 24 No. 6., 1960; Gorlich, P.; Hora, H. (Box 5)
  - "Zur Theorie der Photoemission" Optik 15, 116-126., 1958; Gorlich, P.; Hora, H. (Box 5)
  - "Über die lichtelektrische Richardson-Geliching und eine Theorie der spektralen Verteilung von Photokathoden" Experimentelle Technik der Physik 5 Heft 5, 217-221., 1961; Gorlich, P.; Hora, H.; Mache, W. (Box 5)
  - Fellow, 1955; Institute of Radio Engineers (Box 5)
    Boxed individually
  - "The Revival of Thermoelectricity" Scientific American 199, 31-37., 1958; Joffe, Abram F. (Box 5)
  - Publishing Agreement for Electron Optics, 1959; John Wiley and Sons (Box 5)
  - Royalty statements, 1945-1951; John Wiley and Sons (Box 5)
  - 1950, 1 item; Joliffe, C.B. (Box 5)
    Correspondence
  - "Magnetic Reflection of Electron Beams and Caustic Patterns" Researches 1-18., 1963; Kamakutsu, Hisazo; Kanaya, Koichi; Okazaki, Ikio; Takizawa, Tadao (Box 5)
  - "Electron Beam Trajectory Tracting by Caustic and Shadow Image" Researches 1-16., 1963; Kamakutsu, Hisazo; Kanaya, Koichi; Matsui, Shigeo (Box 5)
  - "Origin of Kx Satellites" Physical Review 46: 1040-1046., 1934; Kennard, E. H., (Earle Hesse), 1885-1968; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 5)
  - "Self-Consistent Field and Some X-Ray Terms of the Sodium Atom" Physical Review, Vol. 46: 1034-1040., 1934; Kennard, E. H., (Earle Hesse), 1885-1968; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 5)
  - "Emission of Auroral Corpuscles in the Vicinity of the Sun", n.d.; Kiepenheuer, K.O. (Box 5)
  - "Studies of Secondary Electron Emission at the Research Institute of the AEG" Jahrbuch der AEG Forschung, 9: 5-17., 1942; Kollath, R. (Box 5)
  - "Die Ausmessung magnetischer Felder an massstablichen Modellen unter Berucksichtigung der Sattigungscheinungen" Optik 11: 171-180., 1954; Langner, G.; Lenz, F. (Box 5)
  - "The Reflected-Beam Kinescope" Proceedings of the IRE. 1409-1417., 1960; Law, Harold B.; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 5)
  - "The Enhanced Scan Post Acceleration Kinescope" RCA Review XXII, No. 4: 603-622., 1961; Davne, L.; Law, Harold B.; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 5)
  - "The Effect of Pole Piece Saturation in Magnetic Electron Lenses" Proceedings of the Physical Society, B 56: 448-458., 1953; Liebmann, G. (Box 5)
  - "The Image Formation on Cathode-Ray Tubes and the Relation of Fluorescent Spot Size and Final Anode Voltage" Proceedings of the IRE 33, No. 6: 383-389., 1945; Liebmann, G. (Box 5)
  - "An Improved Method of Numerical Ray Tracing through Electron Lenses" Proceedings of the Physical Society, B. 57: 753-772., 1949; Liebmann, G. (Box 5)
  - "Magnetic Electron Microscope Projector Lenses" Proceedings of the Physical Society, B. 65: 94-108., 1952; Liebmann, G. (Box 5)
  - "Measured Properties of Strong "Unipotential" Electron Lenses" Proceedings of the Physical Society, B 57: 213-228., 1949; Liebmann, G. (Box 5)
  - "Resistance-Network Analogues" International Analogy Computation Meeting: 346-369., 1955; Liebmann, G. (Box 5)
  - "Solution of Partial Differential Equations with a Resistance Network Analogue" British Journal of Applied Physics 1: 92-103., 1950; Liebmann, G. (Box 5)
  - "The Symmetrical Magnetic Electron Microscope Objective Lens with Lowest Spherical Aberration" Proceedings of the Physical Society B, 54: 972-977., 1951; Liebmann, G. (Box 5)
  - "A Unified Representation of Magnetic Electron Lens Properties" Proceedings of the Physical Society, B. 68: 737-745., 1955; Liebmann, G. (Box 5)
  - "Imaging Properties of a Series of Magnetic Electron Lenses" Proceedings of the Physical Society, B. 54: 956-971., 1951; Grad, E.M.; Liebmann, G. (Box 5)
  - "The M- and N-Series: A Spectroscopic Study of X-Rays" Nova Acta Regiae Societatis Scientiarum Upsaliensis 7, No. 7: 5-75., 1930; Lindberg, Ernst (Box 5)
  - "Thermoelectric Heat Pumping" Electrical Engineering, 1-5., 1958; Lindenblad, N.E. (Box 5)
  - "Development of Equations for the Orientation Error Inherent in a Line-Element Scanner", Dissertation, Rutgers University, 1970; Mifsud, Lewis (Box 5)
  - "Recent Developments in the Scintillation Counter Field" IRE Transactions of the Professional Group on Nuclear Science NS-3, No. 4: 122-135., 1956; Morton, George Ashmun, 1903- (Box 6)
  - "Electron Optics of an Image Tube" Physics 7, No. 12: 451-459., 1936; Morton, George Ashmun, 1903-; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 6)
  - "An Infrared Image Tube and Its Military Applications" RCA Review 7, No. 3: 385-413., 1946; Flory, L.; Morton, George Ashmun, 1903- (Box 6)
  - "Note on the Theory of Interaction of Field and Matter" Physical Review 35, No. 5: 461-477., 1930; Oppenheimer, J. Robert, 1904-1967 (Box 6)
  - "Intensities of Satellites of LB2" Physical Review 46, No. 8: 694-697., 1934; Pearsall, Anna W. (Box 6)
  - "Momentum Distribution in Hydrogen-Like Atoms" Physical Review 34, No. 1: 109-116., 1929; Pauling, Linus, 1901-1994; Podolsky, Boris (Box 6)
  - Television Patents, 1965; Pritchard, Dalton H. (Box 6)
  - "The Selectron-A Tube for Selective Electrostatic Storage" RCA Laboratories News Division, 4 no 2., June 1947; Rajchman, Jan (Box 6)
  - "Aberration Correction with Electron Mirrors" Journal of Applied Physics 20, No. 2: 183-186., 1949; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 6)
  - "Aberrations in Electron Optics" -- Penn State Lecture, Notes, 1964; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 6)
  - "Application of Degrouping Lens with Center and Deflection Plane to 19-inch, (0 Rectangular Color Picture Tube and Effect of Lens Radius on Correction", 1967; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 6)
    Memo to H.B. Law
  - The Atomic Age Review, n.d.; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 6)
  - Bibliography, 1950; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 6)
  - Biographical information, Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 6)
  - "Considerations on Fresnel Lenses for Degrouping Correction" RCA Laboratory Report: 1-23., 1957; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 6)
  - "Correction Lenses for Second-Order Printing of Shadow Mask Screens: Results of Simple Calculations" RCA Laboratories Report., 1962; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 6)
  - "Degrouping Correction and Nesting in Shadow-Mask Kinescopes" RCA Laboratories Report., 1962; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 6)
  - Dielectric Constant from First Principles notes, n.d.; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 6)
  - "Differential Equations of Mathematical Physics", n.d.; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 6)
  - Early History of the Electron Microscope by L. Marton, n.d.; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 6)
    Book review by Ramberg
  - Electron Optic Research, n.d.; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 6)
  - "Electron Optical Properties of a Flat Television Picture Tube" Proceedings of the IRE: 1952-1960., Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 6)
  - Electron Optics -- Aberration, Four Poles, n.d.; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 6)
  - Electron Optics -- Chapter One, n.d.; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 6)
  - Electron Optics --Chapter Three, n.d.; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 6)
  - Electron Optics -- Chapter Four, n.d.; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 6)
  - Electron Optics -- Chapter Descriptions and Correspondence, 1959; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 6)
  - Electron Optics Deflection Notes, n.d.; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 6)
  - [Electron Optics] notes, n.d.; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 6)
  - "Electron Optics and the Electron Microscope", Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 6)
  - "Electron Optics and the Electron Microscope"-Chapter 2 Formerly Chapter 11, Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 6)
  - "Elimination of Moire Effects in Tri-Color Kinescopes" Proceedings of the IRE: 916-923., n.d.; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 6)
  - "The Hologram-Properties and Application" RCA Review 27, No. 4: 467-499., 1966; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 6)
  - "Holographic Applications-a Review and a Forecast" RCA Laboratories Publication., 1970; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 7)
  - "Holographic Information Storage" RCA Review 33, No. 1.: 5-53., 1972; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 7)
  - Improvement in Electron Lens System Patent, 1943; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 7)
  - Institut für Theoretische Physik der Technischen Hochschule Darmstadt: Merkblatt zur Vektorrechnung, 1958; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 7)
  - "Intensity Distribution on s Cathode Ray Tube Spot in the Presence of Thermal Spread, Spherical Aberration and Space Charge Limited Emission" RCA Technical Abstract No. PEM-3191: 1-21., 1969; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 7)
  - Interview and Retirement Speech, 1972; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 7)
  - Lighthouse Printing with Ring Sources, 1972; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 7)
    Memos to H.B. Law
  - Moire Pattern Research, n.d.; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 7)
  - Notecards, n.d.; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 7)
  - Notes, n.d.; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 7)
  - "Optical Factors in the Photoemission of Thin Films" Journal of Applied Optics 6, No. 12: 2163-2170., 1967; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 7)
  - "Optics and Electron Optics as Competitive and Complementary Technologies" Applied Optics 9, No. 10: 2294-2298., 1970; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 7)
  - "Phase Contrast in Electron Microscope Images" Journal of Applied Physics 20, No. 5: 441-444., 1949; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 7)
  - Physics articles and notes in German, Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 7)
  - Physics Materials-Notes, 1953; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 7)
  - Physics notes, n.d.; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 7)
  - Physics notes--1, n.d.; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 7)
  - Physics notes--2, n.d.; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 7)
  - "Probability of Double Jumps in X-Ray Spectra" Physical Review 45: 389-391., 1934; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 7)
  - "Properties of Lighthouse Lenses for Degrouping Correction" RCA Publication, 1956; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 7)
  - Published articles report. American Philosophical Society Miscellanea 1, No. 1. 5-6., 1935; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907-; Richtmyer, F. K., (Floyd Karker), 1881-1939 (Box 7)
  - RCA Correspondence-Incentive Plan, 1952-1967; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 7)
    Engstrom, E.W. and Robert Sarnoff
  - RCA Retirement Speech, 1972; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 7)
  - "Science and God", Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 7)
  - "Sensitivity of Spot Displacement in French Grill Tube", 1971; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 7)
  - "A Simplified Derivation of the General Properties of an Electron-Optical Image" J.O.S.A. 29: 79-83., 1939; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 7)
  - "A Theoretical Analysis of the Operation of Flying Spot and Camera Tube Microscopes in the Ultraviolet" IRE Transactions on Medical Electronics Volume PGME-12: 58-64., 1958; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 7)
  - "Variation of the Axial Aberrations of Electron Lenses with Lens Strength" Journal of Applied Physics 13, No. 9: 582-594., 1942; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 7)
  - 1946, Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 7)
    Letter to Unknown (Bill)
  - "Chromatic Aberration and Resolving Power in Electron Microscopy" Journal of Applied Physics 19, No. 7: 678-682., 1948; Hillier, James; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 8)
  - "Potential Distribution for Space-Charge Limited Current between a Plane Accelerating Grid and Parallel Anode" Journal of Applied Physics. 23, No. 12: 1333-1335., 1952; Malter, L.; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 8)
  - "Electron Optics" Journal of Applied Physics 10, No. 7: 465-478., 1939; Morton, George Ashmun, 1903-; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 8)
  - "Radiation Probabilities, Auger Effect And Energy Level Widths for AU (79)" Physical Review 51, No. 11: 913-925., 1937; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907-; Richtmyer, F. K., (Floyd Karker), 1881-1939 (Box 8)
  - Publishing Agreement for Applied Photoelectricity, 1947; John Wiley & Sons.; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 8)
  - "Über den Mechanismus des elektrischen Lichtbogens" Annalen der Physik 5 folge Bd. 12: 319-352., 1932; Ramberg, Walter, d. 1914 (Box 8)
  - "Multiple Ionization and the Absorption of X-Rays" Philosophical Magazine 6: 64-88., 1928; Richtmyer, F. K., (Floyd Karker), 1881-1939 (Box 8)
  - "Physics is Physics" American Physics Teacher 1, No. 1: 1-5., 1933; Richtmyer, F. K., (Floyd Karker), 1881-1939 (Box 8)
  - "Some Comments on the Classical Theories of the Absorption and Refraction of X-Rays" Philosophical Magazine 6: 1296-1302., 1927; Richtmyer, F. K., (Floyd Karker), 1881-1939 (Box 8)
  - "Some Secondary Phenomena in X-Ray Spectra" Journal of the Franklin Institute 208, No. 3: 325-361., 1929; Richtmyer, F. K., (Floyd Karker), 1881-1939 (Box 8)
  - "A Direct Reading Two-Crystal X-ray Spectrometer" Review of Scientific Instruments 5, No. 10: 351-355., 1934; Barnes, S.W.; Richtmyer, F. K., (Floyd Karker), 1881-1939 (Box 8)
  - "The Natural Widths of the K-Series of W (74)" Physical Review 46, No. 5: 352-356., 1934; Barnes, S.W.; Richtmyer, F. K., (Floyd Karker), 1881-1939 (Box 8)
  - "Widths of the L-Series Lines" Physical Review 46, No. 10: 843-860., 1934; Barnes, S.W.; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907-; Richtmyer, F. K., (Floyd Karker), 1881-1939 (Box 8)
  - "A Device for Reducing Grain Effects in Microphotometer Records" Review of Scientific Instruments 4, No. 6: 353-354., 1933; Hirsh, F.R., Jr.; Richtmyer, F. K., (Floyd Karker), 1881-1939 (Box 8)
  - "X-Ray Satellites of High Atomic Number Elements" Physical Review 44, No. 8: 605-609., 1933; Kaufman, Sidney; Richtmyer, F. K., (Floyd Karker), 1881-1939 (Box 8)
  - "Satellite Structure of Lx and LB2 of AU (79)" Physical Review 51, No. 11: 925-929., 1937; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907-; Richtmyer, F. K., (Floyd Karker), 1881-1939 (Box 8)
  - "Satellites of the X-Ray LinesLa, LB and LB2" Physical Review 34, No. 4: 574-581., 1929; Richtmyer, F. K., (Floyd Karker), 1881-1939; Richtmyer, R. D. (Box 8)
  - "Materials for Thermoelectric Refrigeration" Journal of the Physics and Chemistry of Solids 10, Nos. 2/3, 191-200., 1959; Abeles, Benjamin; Jensen, R.V.; Rosi, F.D. (Box 8)
  - "The Arc Spectrum of Selenium" Physical Review 46, No. 10: 880-888., 1934; Gibbs, R.C., (Roswell Clifton), b. 1878; Ruedy, J.E. (Box 8)
  - RCA Laboratories: A New Center for Radio Research, 1941; Sarnoff, David O.; Schairer, Otto S. (Box 8)
  - "Beam-Deflection and Photo Devices" Proceedings of the IRE 50th Anniversary Issue: 991-1005., 1962; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907-; Schlesinger, K. (Box 8)
  - "Multi-Alkali Photo Cathodes" IRE Transactions of the Professional Group on Nuclear Science, NS-3, No. 4: 1955-1959., 1956; Sommer, Alfred (Box 8)
  - "Ansprache anlasslich der Verheilung der Planck-Medaille an Peter Debye" Physikalische Blatter Jahrgang 6 Heft 11: 509-512., n.d.; Sommerfeld, Arnold, 1868-1951 (Box 8)
  - "Concerning the Shape of the Compton Lines" Physical Review 59: 38-40., 1936; Sommerfeld, Arnold, 1868-1951 (Box 8)
  - "Integrazione asintotica dell'equazione differenziale di Thomas-Fermi" Rendiconti Della R. Accademia Nazionale Dei Lincei 15, 6, 788-792., 1932; Sommerfeld, Arnold, 1868-1951 (Box 8)
  - "Philosophie und Physick Seit 1900" Natureissenschaftlichen Rundschau Heft 3: 97-100., 1950; Sommerfeld, Arnold, 1868-1951 (Box 8)
  - "Das Reziprozitäts-Theorum der drahtlosen Telegraphic", n.d.; Sommerfeld, Arnold, 1868-1951 (Box 8)
  - "Sur quelques problèmes de mechanique ondulatoire", Sommerfeld, Arnold, 1868-1951 (Box 8)
    French
  - "Über den Packungseffekt", n.d.; Sommerfeld, Arnold, 1868-1951 (Box 8)
  - "Über die Hauptschnitte Eines Polydimensionalen Wurfels" Bulletin of the Calcutta Mathematical Society 20, 221-226., 1930; Sommerfeld, Arnold, 1868-1951 (Box 8)
  - "Über die Klein'schen Parameter x,B, y, o und ihre Bedeutung dur die Dirac-Theorie", 1936; Sommerfeld, Arnold, 1868-1951 (Box 8)
  - "X-Ray Spectrosopy and Atomic Structure" Current Science Special Number on "Laue Diagrams: 16-19., 1937; Sommerfeld, Arnold, 1868-1951 (Box 8)
  - "Zum Problem der Maxwellschen Spannungen" Annalen der Physik 6 Folge, Bd 8 Heft 1-2: 41-54., 1950; Bopp, Friedrich Arnold, 1909–1987; Sommerfeld, Arnold, 1868-1951 (Box 8)